Anshu Kumar

Senior Engineer at HERE

anshu.kumar726@gmail.com

Summary

I have 5 years of experience around Enterprise Level Applications (Oracle E-Business Suite and Oracle Sales Cloud). I engage as Developer, Pre-Sales Solution Consultant which gives me clear insight of successful applications. My programming prowess coupled with my products experience will surely help me to build flawless Apps for any business domain. (All views expressed are my personal)

Experience

Senior Engineer at HERE

November 2015 - Present (2 months)

Applications Engineer at Oracle India Pvt. Ltd

March 2015 - November 2015 (9 months)

Role: Cloud Applications Developer Responsible for: --Applications Development --Applications Enhancement --Unit Testing --Defects Resolution

Associate ERP Sales Consultant at Oracle India Pvt. Ltd

June 2013 - February 2015 (1 year 9 months)

Role: Applications Technology Sales Consultant Responsible for: - Building Demos and Proof Of Concepts which included ------Applications Integrations using SOAP web services and APIs ------BI Publisher Reports. - Answering to RFPs and customers ad-hoc questions. - Product Presentations.

Senior Systems Engineer at Infosys

March 2013 - May 2013 (3 months)

Role: Developer ,Tester and E-Business Suite Implementation Consultant for iStore Application Responsible for: - PLSQL APIs. - WebPages using JSP and OAF (a J2EE based framework). - Workflows using Oracle Workflow. - Reports using BI Publisher.

Systems Engineer at Infosys

August 2010 - February 2013 (2 years 7 months)

Role: Developer and Tester Responsible for: - PLSQL APIs. - Workflows using Oracle Workflow.

Certifications

HTML, CSS and JavaScript

Coursera Verified Certificates License AAE2CTYFWT2C October 2015

Oracle PL/SQL Developer Certified Associate

Oracle December 2012

Oracle Database SQL Certified Expert

Oracle June 2012

Front-End Web UI Frameworks and Tools

Coursera Verified Certificates License KDZCG69CAFHW November 2015

Skills & Expertise

Python

JavaScript

Core Java

PL/SQL

SQL

J2EE

Cloud Computing

Oracle Applications

ADF

J2EE Web Services

JSP

Java

Oracle

Oracle 11g

Java Enterprise Edition

PaaS

SaaS

Unix Shell Scripting

Pre/Post Sales Engineers

Education

Lakshmi Narain College Of Technology

Bachelor Of Engineering, COMPUTER SCIENCE ENGG, 2006 - 2010

Bhawan's Sawan Public School

Senior Secondary School, 2003 - 2004

Dayanand Model School

Secondary School, 2001 - 2002

Interests

Playing baminton, carrom, chess. Listening music.

Languages

English

Anshu Kumar

Senior Engineer at HERE

anshu.kumar726@gmail.com



2 people have recommended Anshu

"Anshu's contribution to the team was invaluable in so many aspects. With exceptional technical and analytical skills, he's able to complete his assignments. He's an outstanding team player, Many team members benefited tremendously from his knowledge and mentorship. Definitely an asset to any team!"

— Kiran Basavaraju, Group Manager, Oracle, managed Anshu at Oracle India Pvt. Ltd

"It is with great pleasure to recommend Anshu due to his great results he has achieved for close to two years when he was part of my team. Anshu has the right will, skills and attitude that help an organisation move forward!"

— Catalin CIONTU, Sales Consulting Sr Manager, EMEA Presales Center, Oracle, managed Anshu at Oracle India Pvt. Ltd

Contact Anshu on LinkedIn